Guide to the World Trade Organization 1999 Seattle Ministerial Conference Protest Collection
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- WTO Seattle collection, 1999; 5177-009; 0.42 cubic feet 1 box
  This accession includes newsletters, flyers, and pamphlets relating to issues and events surrounding the WTO conference in Seattle in 1999 that were sent to lawyers at Earthjustice. Earthjustice was a registered NGO at the WTO conference, and specialized in environmental law. Some lawyers had published articles in the newsletters and were supposed to give lectures on Nov. 29, 1999, the day of the rally.
  Open to all users
  Earthjustice, March 26, 2007
- WTO Seattle collection, 1999; 5177-010; 6 cubic feet 1 box, 2 bundles
  Picket signs and other oversize material related to preparation for and participation in the WTO protests of 1999. Created by various organizations, including SPEEA (AFL-CIO), Inland Boatmen's Union, Direct Action Network, and the Sierra Club.
- WTO Seattle collection, 1996-2000; 5177-011; 1 cubic foot 1 box; Includes 7 video recordings
  Booklets, pamphlets, flyers, documents, and videos pertaining to Seattle's WTO protest of 1999. See printed email contents list in box.
  Hans Nesse, July 10, 2008
- WTO Seattle collection, 2000; 5177-012; .03 cubic feet 1 folder
  Cops of the WTO wall calendar featuring photos and commentary about the protests.
  Dan Halligan, April 10, 2013
- WTO Seattle and global justice collection, 1998-2011; 5177-013; 1.64 cubic feet 2 boxes
  Contains publications, fliers, and ephemera relating to the 1999 WTO protests in Seattle, as well as other materials on related issues of global justice, and the Occupy Olympia movement.
  Donor: Trevor Griffey, August 29, 2013
  - Before WTO protests
    - IISD, The World Trade Organization and Sustainable Development: An Independent Assessment: A Report by the International Institute for Sustainable Development, 1996 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Public Citizen’s Global Trade Watch, The World Trade Organization (WTO) at 39 Months: A Sampling of the Damage and Dangers So Far, 1998 March (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Booklets, fliers, etc. about WTO and/or promoting protests, circa 1999 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Handbooks, Action Packet, circa 1999 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Newspapers – Seattle Weekly OVERSIZE, 1999 November 25 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - During WTO protests
    - Publications, articles, clippings, 1999 November (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Newspapers OVERSIZE
      - Seattle Post Intelligencer, 1999 November 28-December 3 (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Seattle Times, 1999 November 29-December 4 (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Seattle Gay News, 1999 December 3 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Seattle Weekly, 1999 December 2 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - The Stranger (clippings), 1999 December 2 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Ephemera – Press badges, small fliers, stickers, parking tickets, ACLU rights cards, button, circa 1999 November (Box-folder 1/6)
    - CD – Christopher DeLaurenti, N30, “Live at the WTO November 30, 1999”, 1999 November 30 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - After WTO protests
    - ACLU of Washington, Out of Control: Seattle’s Flawed Response to Protests Against the World Trade Organization – A Special Report, 2000 July (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Articles, clippings, circa 2000 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Claims against police, circa 2000 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Newspapers OVERSIZE
      - Seattle Times, 1999 December 5-16 (Box-folder 2/5)
      - Seattle Weekly (clippings), 1999 December 9-30 (Box-folder 2/6)
      - The Stranger, 1999 December 9-16 (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Waging War on Dissent: A Report by the Seattle National Lawyers Guild WTO Legal Group, 2000 Winter (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Poster - N29 benefit show OVERSIZE, undated (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Global justice
    - Magazines – In These Times; The Nation; Dollars and Sense; Left Turn, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Jubilee 2000 Coalition, The New Jubilee 2000 Debt Cutter’s Handbook: Breaking the Chains, 1999 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Booklets, small publications, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Newspapers – Eat the State OVERSIZE, 2002 April 24 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Occupy Olympia, 2011 (Box-folder 1/14)
- WTO Seattle collection, 1999-2003; 5177-014; 0.18 cubic feet 1 box Includes 2 video recordings (VHS)
  Marjorie Van Cleef is a teacher and musician with the Bryn Mawr Peace Coalition. She has worked as the Program and Action Chair of the Women's International League for Peace & Freedom.
  VHS tapes, fliers, newspapers, and other publications from and about the World Trade Organization protests in Seattle in 1999, as well as Marjorie Van Cleef’s personal recollections from the demonstrations
  Marjorie Van Cleef, 2015-03-12
  - Marjorie Van Cleef's personal recollections from the WTO demonstrations, undated (Box 1)
  - Shut Down the World Trade Organization newspaper, 1999 (Box 1)
  - The WTO and the Global War System forum proceedings, 1999 (Box 1)
  - "Celebrate Resistance to the WTO" flier, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Clippings from The Stranger, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Clippings from the New Haven Advocate, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Storm Warning! Vietnam Veterans Against the War Anti-Imperialist newsletter, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Neoliberal Globalization: Cancun and Beyond, An In-Depth Report on the World Trade Organization, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Z Magazine, 2000 (Box 1)
  - The Progressive, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Email print-out with the subject "lessons from Seattle and DC", 2000 (Box 1)
  - Indypendent newspaper clipping, undated (Box 1)
  - "Revolt against Globalization" bumper sticker, undated (Box 1)
  - 2 VHS tapes of WTO demonstrations, undated; 2 videocassettes (VHS) (Box 1)
- Ruth Yarrow WTO Seattle protests collection, 1999; 5177-015; 0.18 cubic feet 1 box
  Ruth Yarrow's collection of materials relating to the planning and participation in the World Trade Organizational protests in Seattle in 1999. Ruth Yarrow was involved in the planning and overall events of the 1999 WTO protests in Seattle.
  Ruth Yarrow, 2015-08-25
- World Trade Organization 1999 Seattle Ministerial Conference umbrella, bag, and media guide, 5177-016; 0.52 cubic feet 1 box
  World Trade Organization Seattle Ministerial Conference umbrella, bag, and WTO media guide distributed to reporters covering the 1999 WTO conference in Seattle. This packet was donated by Stacy Sakamoto, a KIRO reporter in Seattle at the time.
  No restrictions on access.
  Donated by Stacy Sakamoto
- "No World Trade Without Workers Rights" WTO protest banner, 1999; 5177-017; 0.70 cubic feet 1 box
  Blue and gold cloth banner with the text "No World Trade Without Workers Rights". The banner was created by made by Carla Kiiskila and David Reynolds on November 29, 1999, on Vashon Island, Washington and was carried the next day by labor movement protesters at the world conference of the WTO in Seattle.
  David Reynolds was a member of International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 763 at the time and became Secretary-Treasurer in 2001. Carla Kiiskila was a legal intern on the International Brotherhood of Teamsters organizing campaign "United for Change," a successful effort to organize apple warehouse workers in Yakima and Wenatchee.
  The banner was proudly carried by labor union members throught the protest against the WTO.
  Blue and gold cloth banner with the text "No World Trade Without Workers Rights." The banner was carried in the labor march protesting the World Trade Organization Ministerial in Seattle, Washington in 1999.
  Access restricted: For terms of access, contact University of Washington Libraries Special Collections.
  Donated by Lilah Smith on behalf of Carla Kiiskila and David Reynolds.